[Music]
i want to be honest here and start by
saying that i don't love the title of
this story that much not because of a bs
pretense that every place in the world
is equally amazing but because i do
truly believe that one's opinion of what
the best and worst place in the world is
is so subjective mostly to one's
experience with its people recently
however the most common question i get
asked in unfortunately 90 of my
interactions is what is my favorite
place i have ever visited i don't like
this question because i don't have an
answer i've been fortunate enough to
travel to obscure places from the least
visited country in the world to the most
boring town in america and have found a
disproportionate amount of kindness
openness and hospitality in many of
these lesser visited places and so
choosing one place over another simply
doesn't make any sense to me as i
recently moved back to europe this led
my curiosity to eventually google the
strange question of what does the
internet believe the worst country in
europe is and i landed on multiple
websites with unfortunately the same
answer of moldova
now the answer to why is obviously
difficult as the soviet union fell apart
in 1991 a power grab led lots of
corruption in the country and a very
challenging time for moldovans with
country-wide economic strain this led to
a lack of government funding for wages
housing and infrastructure for decades
which resulted in many of the streets
and buildings becoming decrepid and over
one third of the entire population
leaving in the past 30 years and so as
an attempt to once again hopefully prove
the opinion of the internet wrong we
decided to fly the moldova for three
days and see what unusual adventure
we could find to commemorate our travels
from last year to transnistria the
country that doesn't exist on a map that
is technically located inside the
borders of moldova i brought my friend
eric who speaks fluent russian i'm very
excited that i get to go to uh
supposedly the worst country in europe
as we celebrate seekers day for this
entire week and an incredible seven
years of creating stories on this
channel our all-time best sellers on
steep discomfort.com are all 30 off
right now for only the next seven days
with the code seeker at checkout which
will be our only sale of the year we
decided to bring back one of our most
memorable strangers we met on the street
stefan from sweden who agreed to swap
lives with another stranger from the u.s
three years ago to join us today when i
woke up i was looking in my wardrobe but
i one t-shirt left and the t-shirt says
and so with the dream team assembled we
were extremely excited to discover what
moldova had to offer
baby yeah we're the all-new
foreigners coming here right now
everyone's staring at us
[Music]
i got a nice little tourist map i think
it'll tell us exactly what we need to do
here oh dude it says uh absolutely
nothing
look at this beauty
whoa
huh
oh how lovely
oh here's our hotel
look at this this is so nice
well our moldovan adventure officially
begins
[Music]
as soon as we step out there's like all
the buildings with graffiti on them and
like brand new
buildings right here every block or so
there's like a pretty big abandoned
building i see a lot of european flags
the flags of the eu so why are there
flags are they trying to become a part
of the eu
future
future great thank you
youtube they're trying to become a part
of the european union but they're not
they haven't been accepted yet we have
absolutely no plan right now we are
literally just trying just walking
around like an entourage we are just
looking to meet moldova basically and
although we walked out of the door of
our hotel with the only plan of finding
the rusty soviet amusement park the city
still has we could never have predicted
that the person we were about to meet
next was going to completely transform
our trip i'm gonna ask this one
[Music]
friend and talk tell me his whole life
he's singing in the background now great
listener i haven't met everything you're
listening for two hours we were just
asking if there was an amusement park
and we got stuffed for an hour and a
half why is none of this on the internet
what about moldova this is really nice
this is so beautiful i said it was like
the worst place on earth it's so
beautiful look at this little plaza oh
this is the pickup
he wants to show us something okay so
this wonderful man mikhail is just
taking us somewhere he's uh not taking
no for an answer and he's like i'm going
to show you some stuff
where are we going
this place is called drunk cherry okay i
said what should we order they said we
only have one drink
wait is he not joining us
i think we've just met the most
spontaneous
elderly man in moldova and while eric
was listening to mikhail's entire life
story we got recognized by two moldovan
subscribers i know we had people that
knew also
who gave us some insight into what the
youth think about moldova's future our
last president who was like very like
communist and with like russia like he
really wanted to blend our countries
together back today you are like uh
yeah but like our new president she's so
amazing with the leadership we have
right now if we continue on this path
we'll definitely like we just got
elected to be like hopefully in the
future to be part of the european union
i'm not all brainwashed we're not all
pro russians broke with him there's a
lot of us that like actually want to
change and actually hope for the better
yeah wow i'm getting like goosebumps
over my entire body you can like record
it right now
what is happening in mikhail's story
oh he's telling me a lot of stuff are
you guys telling me about his military
career
[Laughter]
hello
yeah
make a film yeah enjoy wow thank you
enjoy thank you so much see you moldova
kindness this is what happens when you
go to places that nobody visits everyone
is just excited to see that people are
visiting yeah mikhail had beef with that
guy
just arrived at one of the main
monasteries of the country
whoa
[Music]
is
accept your
[Music]
i was asking him like if he knows that
guy that he clearly has beef with and
he's like yeah that guy like he tries to
get money from people and he always hits
him with a stick because he's like get
away like stop messing with my thing and
mikhail didn't want you guys to get
scammed by the dude he's really our
grandfather
grandpa is eating some food
how's grandpa doing
and he goes
[Music]
i just found out his family story
his whole family wearing a car got hit
by a truck wife his daughter
and her
husband
they all died in the same in one car
accident
it's the craziest thing his wife
his grandson daughter and her husband
but like he's like doesn't really want
to like frown upon that because it's
been a long time since this happened so
yeah
he's like a guy from up
he's really an adventurer
how could when why are you celebrating
away from him because he told us earlier
he loves to go on road trips to like
different places when he gets bored and
totally bailed on his plan today to join
us
after spending the morning getting to
know michael we said our goodbyes
we're not going to say goodbye we're not
going to say goodbye guys we'll see each
other later ventured off again in the
search of the old soviet amusement park
we were looking for at the start of our
day oh this is it it looks very
abundant it looks very abandoned i would
be shocked if any of these rides are
still working
holy
is this one safe
yeah can we do a quick lie detector test
this is the rustiest ride in this entire
place my mom is gonna kill me
look at this seat like i'm really really
scared of hiding stop shaking you're
shaking oh my god it's so hot
oh my god oh my god oh my
oh my god we're not doing this though
that's all stefan remember
safely
wow that goes fast oh my god dude oh my
god
oh my god
[Laughter]
well the park is closing we survived
another abandoned soviet amusement park
on our way out of the park we happened
to meet a family of ukrainian refugees
how has it been because it's still once
my parents and my wife parents at home
as well
we had the apartments there and this
apartments and just now it can be
bumped by one swept
hopefully man hopefully yep somewhere
soon
this is my
this is my older one
that's it
so real man their family like walking
here and
experience all this pain so
[Music]
you saw this suffering in the world
right for a new reason of all like it's
just so unfair so let's keep spreading
love guys right yeah
it's crazy to think about though i
didn't realize the amount of stress that
moldova probably has
because
if the war expands it comes
with that wow
people are gonna go in here
because there are ukrainians here there
are moldovans and then we just met a guy
who grew up in russia and lives here
conflict must be super strange because
there's so many there's so much overlap
right i really didn't expect moldova to
be such a
melting pot yeah you know but it but it
is really
it makes it like a very special country
actually at the moment right
real fun
family energy
well definitely yeah come from welcome
to moldova yeah this time everywhere
around the world it's just always the
most positive
kind and open-minded people it's it's
crazy it's crazy we thought this was
just a brief encounter with the
subscriber until moments later this
happened
i can go what are we doing we're gonna
have fun fun let's go
did you just abandon your friend no i
just sent him to him
there are some nights when we start
filming and we don't really know what
we're filming
this is one of them
we've arrived
this is very different than what it was
earlier today moldova in three one two
three
tell him that we're happy he's here
he said i'm really happy i found you
guys oh can you be our adopted grandpa
one more time
get that dress you can call him grandpa
grandpa the thing is we literally don't
have his contact we just keep running
into him he doesn't have a phone
he likes to swim are we going to the
beach with him tomorrow i think so
talking to mikhail i can't fully
understand what's going on but he kind
of seems a little bit like a nomad like
he doesn't really have a place to stay
tonight he's going to the doctor because
he's got an issue with his foot so he
was just going to sleep at the hospital
stay at our hotel tonight and he was
like yeah maybe let's see how the night
goes also something that i forgot to
mention so far was that at midnight it
would actually be my birthday and the
clock
just struck 12.
[Applause]
thanks for reminding me thank you thank
you grandpa we just met some uh really
nice girls and mikael is giving stuff on
dating advice he's like yo if you're
going to talk to girls you got to
entertain them you got to tell them
stories
we're going to joe's house tonight and
where is it joe
when you go out in other countries
sometimes they're like ah tourists are
here here it's like
buddhists are here it's like an
attraction it's like let's find out
where they're from look bro come with us
let's go party bro
[Music]
you thought that was an ad didn't you
it's not it's a part of the video it's a
part of the video you can't skip this
one
well they could skip it please move
forward please please please today marks
seven years of yes theory and today
seekers day which is something we've
been celebrating the past three years
where we put all of the best sellers
from seekdiscomfort.com 30 off it's the
only time of the year we put any kind of
discount on seek discomfort and it is a
way to kind of say thank you three
percent is a lot that's a big discount
it's like if if something was 100 that
means i could get it for 30 instead no
no
there are 300 000 people who have bought
from seek discomfort in 180 countries we
keep running into people all over the
world who wear it it's just like an
amazing tool for connection seek
discomfort allows us to have the freedom
to go after the trips that we want to go
after so thank you for supporting us it
would mean the world to us if you go to
seekdiscomfort.com right now 30 off so
we highly recommend you go check it out
right now
and
i guess back to grandpa
we have two hotel rooms he's gonna take
one of them and the three of us will
share one little slumber party yeah
how do you feel about this keep
continuing to remind me mikhail thank
you the hotel is gonna be so confused
these three young tourists came they
went out until two in the morning and
they brought back a 74 year old local
grandpa
there's a bunch
[Music]
he's such a funny man he just like takes
life as it comes like there's no level
of like oh i'm in this hotel now like
guys this is a crazy thing he's just
like okay i sit here and this is my life
this is my room he just she's just here
now
new level
literally he's a kung matata he's just
taken as it comes
[Music]
he's just butt naked showering
no he's naked
don't touch it it's dry okay is this how
you imagine your
birthday is going on right now
[Music]
mikhail hasn't had a phone this whole
time so we haven't been able to reach
him he doesn't know what time it is so
we're just going to get him a phone
exactly he said i used to i used one to
call people i used to know the time yeah
that's only once but but he was also
like i'm gonna buy it we were like we'll
get it for you he's like no i'm gonna
buy it i'm like no dude let us get you
this nokia no store okay
you got a phone
[Music]
it really does feel like he's the real
life up character by the way he's he's
very sweet and kind of grumpy eric is
like the little character and a little
scout who like keeps trying to take care
of grandpa and grandpa's like ah
whatever he's super smart i just can't
piece his life together
toyota
see i don't know what to do with that
information sometimes i can't
so far mikhail's life was really one big
mystery to us so we decided to sit him
down and ask him a few questions
[Music]
i think trying to understand how does he
survive right
[Music]
can you ask him if he's comfortable
telling us a bit about what happened
foreign
[Music]
is
tell him like we know that um
like pension here is not very high and
what not and we just wanted to
help him and give him this letter and he
doesn't have to open
um he has no idea but we just gave him
five hundred dollars which is ten
thousand of the local currency so you
just gave him uh
eight months of his
account he won't know that until he
opens he probably has no idea what he
doesn't probably doesn't even know that
there's money in there no i don't i
don't think he thinks there's like a
letter yeah we're we're really grateful
that you've been such a big part of our
experience
absolutely
literally we're just following this man
we just asked him for directions to a
park and now our entire life depends on
him yeah is this the right bus we're
going an hour away from here
what is he trying to do oh he was trying
to pay for our ticket
no
hi man
he's always like just leave everyone
alone he's like anyone who's not a part
of the boys
[Music]
each day with grandpa
this is the best birthday ever
freaking crazy grandpa taking us around
the least visiting country
[Music]
with our beach adventure over it was
time to get mikhail a fancy new outfit
for a party at a castle that a stranger
had invited us to tonight we're in like
a really nice italian tailor right now
we're a little bit out of place
however with only three tickets to the
event we had to sneak in grandpa
while we've arrived at a traditional
festival at a castle
that's really good wine
[Music]
so we are here completely on our own
without the people who invited us today
is my birthday and somehow i ended up at
a castle in the least visited country
from europe
going along with the flow
and after four hours of enjoying the
event at the castle we once again lost
grandpa where is mikhail yeah we're
looking for michaela mikhail mikhail
where is he
grandpa have you seen this old grandpa
oh
miguel is lost it was like like three or
four five hours ago three four hours ago
grandfather grandpa's missing and he's
had wine that's not good
he might have gone down maybe he went
down that way okay let's cut through
that thank you
[Music]
he was on the dance floor
other pieces
[Music]
while you pet his hands it's fully
comfortable that you get him i'm a
complete stranger all right grandpa
we love you
love you man
he said i love you
yeah he did say he love you
not
and what i'm finding so fascinating
about him is that he's always like
telling us let's go you would think that
someone who's 74 and doesn't really
happen
he said this looks like a piano he likes
to observe he's very observant but
he says let's go stand up like he's
telling let's march outside
isn't it
[Music]
he can have mine he can have mine
did he have fun
of course
he just
fell asleep on the bench
we
[Laughter]
[Music]
you're so excited he's like you got to
read this thing this is his organization
that like created this whole monument
for this famous captain in the war we
actually couldn't have had a better
guide to the city i know the dude knows
everything grandpa was saying missions
are done everything on his checklist is
over now if we want to just hit the bell
here at the cemetery then we can go home
we can do whatever we want his job is
done once this bell is ringing
michelle's mission will be accomplished
he just whistles away
there's a story here
[Laughter]
oh
what did i say what did i say
and thomas oh
grandpa
i mean yeah
[Music]
grandpa's taking us to the airport he
wants to send us off and
that's the weirdest thing ever
[Music]
heading to the airport with bonnello and
i said how are you gonna get back to the
city and he said what do you think i'm
gonna end up in paris or something i'm
gonna i'll figure it out we also gave
him the number to the grandma we met in
uh transnistria so he's excited to maybe
meet her as well when he goes to
you said i'm grandpa and she's grandma
grandpa is dropping us off
putting his shoes
on
yeah
but yes
[Music]
need i'm gonna love you to the end of
time
because a love like us is hard to find
[Music]
that's the saddest thing i've ever
experienced
you really feel that
this is exactly why i don't like the
question of what i think the best and
worst place is because at the end of the
day it is impossible to predict an
experience like this one for a place
that seemed pointless to visit according
to the internet moldova really had so
many great things to offer and is
seemingly on track to a brighter future
but we ended up discovering this place
through the eyes of mikhail and had a
much more meaningful trip than we could
possibly have ever orchestrated
ourselves
if you do decide to go visit moldova
there's plenty to do and see but my
personal recommendation would be to try
and go find michael roaming around the
drunk cherry bar take him out for a
lunch and make his day and your own a
little bit brighter
as an unusual addition to the strangers
we've gone on adventures with we
couldn't have imagined a better way to
celebrate seven years on this channel
final reminder that seekers day is live
right now for this week only on
seekdiscomfort.com using the code seeker
for our only sale of the year with 30
off our all-time best sellers it would
mean the world to us if you went to
seekdiscomfort.com and found some
clothing you loved and repped wherever
you go we are about to take our yearly
break in august so we will probably see
you in september
[Music]